SRUTI CHEEDALLA

UX DEVELOPER & DESIGNER



703.203.4025

✓ scheedalla@gmail.com

https://scheedalla.github.io

PROFILE

Versatile and motivated UX Developer, Designer, and Researcher with over 10+ years of experience working on responsive web applications on Agile teams. I can conduct research and build prototypes and then manage the full development stack and deploy to the cloud.

SKILLS

Development

HTML5, SASS/CSS3, Javascript, React + Redux + Webpack, Angular, AngularJS, Node.js, jQuery, Express, Grunt, Gulp, MongoDB, SQL, Java

Design

Interaction Design, Interactive Prototyping, Responsive Design (Web and Mobile), Accessibility

Research

Card Sorting, Heuristic Evaluations, Usability Testing, Surveys, User Interviews

Other

Git, SVN, Agile, DevOps (AWS, Jenkins), Jira. Confluence

CERTIFICATIONS

NN/G UX Certificate Professional Scrum with User Experience

EDUCATION

M.S. Information Systems GEORGE MASON UNIVERSITY / DEC 2010

B.A. History / Minor Mathematics UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA / MAY 2007

CONFERENCES

Starting from Scratch with the MEAN Stack MONGODB WORLD, NYC / JUN 2015

When Being MEAN is a Good Thing WOMEN IN TECH SUMMIT / MAR 2016

The Washington Post Developer Dav ORGANIZER / 2015, 2017, 2018

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Principal UI/UX Designer/Developer (Active DoD Secret Clearance) NORTHROP GRUMMAN / JAN 2020 - PRESENT

- Create low and high fidelity prototypes to demonstrate to clients and cross-functional teams
- Research, analyze, and implement Accessibility improvements
- Create, code, and debug React components
- · Collaborate with cross-functional team on requirements and deployment strategies
- Conduct testing sessions on prototypes
- Conduct user research such as interviews and card sorting
- Mentor team members on UX and front-end web development
- Conduct learning sessions on Agile, React ecosystem, and UX
- Provide feedback on production customer support inquiries

Senior Web Developer

THE WASHINGTON POST / APR 2015 - JAN 2020

- · Coordinated and worked closely with UX designers and product owners on creating cohesive, responsive designs
- Implemented and maintained new responsive, reusable, performant redesign of existing sign-in web application w/1 million + users using React, Redux, and Webpack
- Led team on deployment strategy and coordination with other teams for the new web and mobile application
- Integrated formalized code review process for developers to provide greater transparency and documentation
- Led and managed team that orchestrated Developer Day 2017 & 2018, an internal conference
- Coded new components in React, AngularJS, and jQuery
- Enhanced customer service and offer management tools using Angular and Webpack

Web Developer

THE WASHINGTON POST / AUG 2011 - APR 2015

Grew from front-end developer to a full stack senior developer with experience building SASS and Javascript frameworks, writing APIs, managing databases, and maintaining AWS infrastructure.

- · Built and designed from the ground up, a new dynamic form builder and curation tool using the MEAN Stack
- · Regularly collaborated with design, product, and development on the direction of products
- Maintained infrastructure of web application on AWS and integrated Elasticsearch to refine search
- Architected and built one of the first applications at company to use a front-end responsive framework for Home Sales redesign using Bootstrap and Javascript libraries
- · Led implementing existing Washington Post navigation header and footer on all commercial product sections
- Built new features for the Paywall, new project to limit articles and allow users to purchase subscriptions
- Built Home Sales trending tool: a choropleth map superimposed on Google maps and a chart with interactive slider
- Designed and built search tool for "Ask Warren Brown" that searched all Real Wheel bi-weekly chats

User Interface Design Intern

MIXNET CORP / AUG 2010 - JAN 2011

Led creation of and redesigned front-end user interface for application efileTaxPro to increase usability, consistency and overall effectiveness of program using ASP.NET, XHTML, and CSS.

Web Intern

N.E.W. CUSTOMER SERVICES COMPANY / SUMMER 2010

Debugged and solved front-end issues for the ServiceBench software application, web-based service management solutions for the appliance industry.

Webmaster and Graduate Assistant

HONORS COLLEGE GMU / SEP 2009 - JUL 2010

Developed and maintained websites for the Postgraduate Fellowships and Scholarship, Undergraduate Apprentice programs, and Honors Curriculum.

Intern

SWIFT / SUMMER 2009

Developed and maintained website for the Internal Audit department, reorganized shared data and created an index database, and proposed policy for audit file retention..

Graduate Assistant

OFF-CAMPUS & TRANSFER STUDENT SERVICES UMBC / SEP 2009 - JUL 2010

Kept crucial info current on the department website and spearheaded online promotion of all events and provided technology support for the 3 member staff and 8 commuter assistants.

Assistant Director/Personal Academic Tutor

SCORE! EDUCATIONAL CENTERS / JUL 2007 - JUL 2008

Supervised over 200 members' academic progress using computer database and analyzed customer needs to determine best product or service fit; became familiar with marketing and sales strategies.

Intern

DEFENSE THREAT REDUCTION AGENCY, DOD / SUMMER 2005, SUMMER 2006

Received Confidential DoD Security Clearance, assisted Business Directorate, Facilities, Logistics, and Mission Support Chief, in administrative duties.

Office Assistant

CENTER FOR SOUTH ASIAN STUDIES UVA / JAN 2005 - MAY 2007

Coordinated graduate student applications for Foreign Language Fellowship Program, maintained the video library catalog for the Southeast Region, marketed South Asian related courses and events, and performed administrative duties.